

Contact

LinkedIn albertksigman26

GitHub

NightingaleMedia

Albert Sigman Full Stack Developer Columbus, OH

About Me

Full stack developer on a mission to solve problems creatively with technology. Informed by 10+ years of design-driven project management. Passionate about elegant system design UX, data science, data visualization, immersive installations, IoT and embedded systems. Four plus years agency experience ranging from NYC startups to nation-wide corporations.

Stack

Java Git

Spring Javascript

Hibernate/H2 Python d3.js

React.is

Django

HTML/CSS

PHP

Agile/Scrum

REST API

SQL RaspberryPi Linux Bash Recent Projects

Lumens Web App

Python, Django, Twilio API, JavaScript

Created a customized video-consultation application for interior design. The app ties to mobile devices for a consultation then sends recommended products directly.

Random Access Cards

Java, Spring, Javascript, Git

With a team of 4 other remote developers, we created a game-like study tool. Developed as a single page application with Java providing a REST API and Javascript rendering the front end.

Achievements

Achieved aggregate of \$1,500,000 in grand funding from the EPA

Collaborated, developed and launched enterprise-grade web app "Lumens"

Produced and managed broadcast TV ads for global commercial brands.

Education

BA Urban Revitalization Indiana Univeristy 2013 GPA 3.45

Cert. Software Development We Can Code IT 2020

Industry Experience

Business Dev Manager | Cleanlites Recycling Inc Sep 2013 - Dec 2019

- Achieved \$1.5 Million in grant funding as project lead for the grant-writing team.
- Delivered earnings growth 20% YoY through research-driven aguisitions and strategy.
- Spearheaded, organized and executed nation-wide corporate re-branding.

Oct 2017 - Present Founder & CEO | Nightingale Media

- Earned and retained clients through beating deadlines and exceeding expectations.
- Used technical & design skills to develop and communicate brand messaging.
- Solely managed 4-6 corporate clients while rolling out deadline-contingent projects.

Production Intern | Antfood Studios NYC May 2017 - Nov 2017

- Designed, coded and developed interactive audio installations as a team member.
- Edited and composed nationally syndicated ads for global brands and clients.
- Managed and coordinated entire project life-cycles from kickoff to shipment.

Marketing Associate | Complex Ventures NYC

- Advised, consulted and developed better branding and UX for e-commerce clients.
- Managed complete marketing strategies for B2C clients and national brands.
- Created and produced the From Day One Podcast, covering startups in Brooklyn, NY.